YINWEI ZHANG

 \blacksquare zhangyinwei1994@gmail.com \cdot $\$ (+1) 520-486-7382 \cdot in YINWEI \cdot $\$ https://yinwei-zhang.github.io/

≜ Summary

Ph.D. candidate in Industrial Engineering. Masters in Statistics. 1.5 years of industrial experience in developing/deploying deep learning models. Solid theoretical background in machine learning and statistical methods. Proficiency in Python, data science libraries, deep learning frameworks, and SQL. Self-motivated individual with excellent communication and presentation skills.

Education

University of Arizona, United States

Ph.D. Candidate in Industrial Engineering
Master of science in Statistics&Data Science
Master of science in Engineering Management

Aug, 2018 - May, 2023 (Expected) Aug, 2020 - Dec, 2022 (Expected) Aug, 2016 - May, 2018

Jingchu University of Technology, China

Bachelor of science in Process Equipment and Control Engineering

Sep, 2012 - Jul, 2016

Related Coursework: Fundamental of Optimization, Experimental Design, Theory of Probability & Statistics, Statistical Machine Learning, Database Design in SQL, Project Management

Technical Proficiencies

- Soft skills: communication, writing, leadership
- Platforms: Windows, MacOS, Linux, Docker
- Programming skills: Python, R, Matlab, SAS, SQL
- Software & Libraries: TorchLua, TensorFlow/PyTorch, Lua, Sklearn, Numpy, Pandas Blender, ROS, CARLA, Autoware

Experiences

Research Intern, ABB, Raleigh, NC

Jan, 2020 - Aug, 2021

- ullet Worked with international teams, proposed a novel **data collection** mechanism that increases the efficiency by 50%
- Developed the **data pre-processing** pipeline such as data cleaning and format converting by Numpy and Pandas
- Trained the neural networks parallelly for image based regression or segmentation tasks in a Linux multi-GPU server
- Deployed the trained neural networks by using TensorFlow Serving in the Docker container
- Achieved 30% improvement in testing accuracy by designing a novel 3D data augmentation algorithm in Python
- Significantly enhanced the interpretability of the NN to the image features by developing a mask-based method
- Visualized the results using TensorBoard/matplotlib, and presented to the global technical manager
- Cooperated with project managers and lawyers to generate 3 patents and write 2 scientific reports

President, INFORMS Student Chapter, University of Arizona

Sep, 2021 - Present

- Lead the chapter members to collaborate with the department for organizing social events
- Analyze students' demands and initiate a new series of workshop that is helpful to students
- Collaborated with American Airline and held recruiting event at the department successfully

Teaching Assistant, Quality Engineering, University of Arizona

Jan, 2021 - May, 2021

- Supported learning unsupervised anomaly detection based on statistical modeling
- Demonstrated supervised model selection/training for efficient anomaly detection with historical well-labeled data
- Illustrated model evaluation based on confusion matrix, i.e., true positive, true negative, false positive, and false negative

Teaching Assistant, Fundamentals of Data Science for Engineers, University of Arizona Aug, 2021 - Dec, 2021

- Supported learning principles of data pre-processing, e.g., data correcting, data completing, data creating, and data converting
- Assisted in understanding algorithms for supervise/unsupervise learning
- Demonstrated Python and libraries, e.g., Sklearn, Numpy, and Pandas

Projects

Error Occurrence Prediction for AV System (collaboration with Intel Lab), Tucson, AZ

2022

- Developed a physics-based simulation pipeline in **Docker** for studying the AV system in Linux environment
- Modified Python modules for RGB and point cloud data fusion, improved the robustness of the decision-making
- Proposed a model can **predict** the error occurrences with **40% improvement** in MAE compared with the benchmark method

Anomaly Detection via Statistical Learning, Tucson, AZ

2019

- Regularized the model coefficients with L_1 or L_2 regularizations to encourage the smoothness and the sparsity
- Designed a gradient-based algorithm to estimate parameters **parallelly**, reduced the complexity from $O(n^3)$ to $O(n \log n)$
- The method can be applied to CT images and the result shows that the F1 score is improved by 15%

Object Detection via UAV with A Moving Camera, Tucson, AZ

2018

- Preprocessed the frames in OpenCV and tracked features in each frame by LK optical flow
- Proposed a method based on **perspective transformation** and conducted frame differencing and post-processing such as thresholding, **connected component analysis**, and **morphological operations**
- The results show that the proposed method achieves 33% improvement in F1 score and 10 FPS in a CPU

Coursework Project on Product Assessment, Tucson, AZ

2018

- Collected one batch of products and measured the weight for each product
- Estimated the sample mean and sample variance of the weight
- Built hypothesis to test the equality between the mean weight and the designated weight by T-test
- The **p-value** showed that the weight for this batch is significant

Presentation

- Xia, S., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J. (2020). Investigation of Curing Process Heterogeneity from Raman Spectrum via CP Decomposition. *INFORMS Annual Meeting*.
- **Zhang, Y.** (2019). Tutorial: Applications of Spatial-Temporal Data Analytics in Industry. *Grand Lab Slam Workshop*, University of Arizona, Tucson.
- **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., Lansey, K. (2019). Functional Data Analytics for Detecting Bursts in Water Distribution Systems. *IN-FORMS Annual Meeting*, Seattle.
- **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., Son, Y. (2018). Effective and Efficient Moving Object Detection by a Moving Camera, *INFORMS Annual Meeting*, Phoenix.

Publication

- Pan, F., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., Head, L., Elli, M., & Alvarez, I. (2022). Quantifying error propagation in multi-stage perception system of autonomous vehicles via physics-based Simulation. *Winter Simulation Conference*, Singapore.
- Zhang, Y., Zhang, T., Liu, J., Kang, W., Liang, R., & Potter, B. (2022). Profile extraction for optical lens curing process with Image-based Regularized Tensor Decomposition. *Proceedings of the 2022 International Symposium on Flexible Automation*, Japan.
- Zhang, T., **Zhang, Y.**, & Liu, J., Smooth-sparse decomposition in the image based on alternative smooth direction Model, (on-going).
- Nikravesh, Y., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., & Frantziskonis, G.N (2022). A partition and microstructure-based method for large-scale topology optimization. *Mechanics of Materials*, Volume 166.
- Peterson, R. L., Shea, K. D., Liu, J., Luque, K., Powell, J., **Zhang, Y**., Williams, D. K., Martin-Plank, L., Heasley, B. J., Phillips, L. R., & Crist, J. D. (2021). Family caregiving context: a pilot study. *The Arizona Nurse*, April.
- **Zhang, Y.**, Lansey, K., & Liu, J. (2020). Detecting bursts in water distribution system via penalized functional decomposition. IEEM Conference (honorable mention award).
- Lee, S., Jain, S., **Zhang, Y.**, Liu, J., & Son, Y. (2020). A multi-paradigm simulation for the implementation of digital twins in surveillance application. IISE Conference.
- Lee, S., Jain, S., Yuan, Y., **Zhang, Y.**, Yang, H., Liu, J., & Son, Y. (2019). Design and development of a DDDAMS-based border surveillance system via UVs and hybrid simulations. *Expert Systems With Applications*, 109-123.

Patent

- System and method to generate augmented training data for neural network, No. PCT/US21/37798
- Robotic systems and methods used with installation of component parts
- Robotic systems and methods used to update training of a neural network based upon neural networks outputs